adrive.com 2018-12-28

# ADrive | Online Storage, Online Backup, Cloud Storage | Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

(Revised May 23, 2018)

Welcome to ADrive’s privacy policy. This policy sets forth ADrive's information sharing practices and is incorporated into and is subject to the ADrive Terms of Service (the “TOS”). You may access this Policy and the TOS at [www.adrive.com/terms](http://www.adrive.com/terms). Capitalized words within the Privacy Policy not defined herein have the meaning given to them in the Agreement. By using ADrive Services, You expressly consent to ADrive's use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### A. Information Collection and Use.

ADrive is an on-line storage solution where users can upload, store, and access files of their choice remotely. In connection with these services, ADrive collects certain personal information about visitors and users to ADrive’s website and services. The most common type of information collected includes things like user names, passwords, email addresses, IP addresses, and other contact information, as well as payment information and transactional details for ADrive users. This information is commonly collected automatically as ADrive users navigate ADrive’s website and service offerings.ADrive is an on-line storage solution where users can upload, store, and access files of their choice remotely. In connection with these services, ADrive collects certain personal information about visitors and users to ADrive’s website and services. The most common type of information collected includes things like user names, passwords, email addresses, IP addresses, and other contact information, as well as payment information and transactional details for ADrive users. This information is commonly collected automatically as ADrive users navigate ADrive’s website and service offerings.

Once stored by a user on ADrive’s servers, ADrive and its personnel do not view, investigate, manipulate, alter, process, sell, offer for sale, or make independent determination or inquiry into the contents of files stored on its site. Except where otherwise required by law, ADrive does not assume any responsibility for said files, which remain solely the responsibility of the user(s) who uploaded them onto ADrive’s servers.

Except as required by law, subpoena, or court order, ADrive will not sell, share, or rent this information to others except as permitted by this Privacy Policy.

### B. Registration.

In order to use the ADrive Services, Users must first complete a registration form containing information used to identify the specific User. This information is also used to enforce ADrive's Policy Against Copyright Infringement and its Terms of Service. The User may provide optional identifying information, demographic information, and unique identifiers to enable us to provide a more personalized experience on the Site.

### C. Cookies and Other Technologies.

ADrive uses technologies like cookies and pixel tags to provide, improve, protect and promote ADrive Services. For example, cookies help us with things like remembering your username for your next visit, understanding how you are interacting with ADrive Services, and improving them based on that information. You can set your browser to not accept cookies, but this may limit your ability to use the ADrive Services.

Some of ADrive's business partners use cookies and other technologies for purposes such as serving ads and measuring advertising effectiveness. ADrive, however, has no access to or control over their use of these cookies and is not responsible for the data collected through these cookies, or how any such collected data is used or shared by ADrive's business partners. Any information that third parties collect via cookies and other technologies is completely anonymous.

### D. Log Files.

ADrive uses IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the ADrive Services, and track usage. Users’ IP addresses are linked to personally identifiable information for security and operational purposes only.

### E. Correspondence.

ADrive may retain correspondence from Users. Except as required by law or to assist in enforcing the ADrive Terms of Service, such correspondence will be used for tracking purposes only. ADrive will not use it for any secondary purpose or to send You unsolicited electronic mail. Personal Basic Accounts and Free Trial Users will receive advertising and other electronic mail from ADrive affiliates and partners.

### F. Use of Personal Information.

Except as set forth in Your preferences, ADrive will not give, sell, rent, share, or trade any personal information about You to third parties or provide Your personal information, including your name or electronic mail address, to third parties except as required by law, subpoena or court order, and/or as ADrive believes necessary or appropriate in connection with an investigation for fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other potentially illegal activity and/or for dispute resolution and enforcement of the ADrive Terms of Service. ADrive may share aggregated demographic information with its partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

### G. Metadata.

By Your use of the ADrive Services, You grant a non-exclusive, sub-licensable license to ADrive for any and all rights in the identifications, descriptions, or other metadata you have provided in connection with your Storage Data. ADrive reserves the right to rent, sell or otherwise share this metadata with other entities at its discretion.

### H. Special Offers.

ADrive may occasionally send information on products, services, special deals, or a newsletter to its Users. Premium and Business Account Users may opt out of receiving these types of communications. Please see ADrive's Choice/Opt-Out provision below.

### I. Security.

ADrive uses available best practices to protect our Users' personal information. When ADrive asks Users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is protected with SSL encryption software for transmission to ADrive. All of our Users' information is restricted in our offices. Only employees or contractors who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information.

### J. Site and Service Updates.

From time to time, it may be necessary for ADrive to send Users important update announcements via electronic mail.

### K. Choice/Opt-out.

Premium and Business Account Users may opt-out of having their information used for purposes not directly related to the ADrive Services. Premium or Business Account Users who no longer wish to receive promotional materials from our partners may opt-out of receiving these communications via the settings page.

### L. Unlawful Activity by Third Parties.

Though ADrive utilizes industry-standard encryption technology to protect User content from unauthorized access, ADrive cannot warrant and does not guarantee against unlawful interception or access to transmissions or private communications by a third party. 

### M. Advertising.

If You are a Personal Basic Account User, we use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when You visit our website. Depending on Your preferences, these companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about Your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to You. If You would like more information about this practice and to learn about Your right to opt-out of having this information used by third parties, click here.

### N. European Union Data Protection Law (GDPR).

For the purposes of applicable EU data protection law, including, without limitation, the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (GDPR), in some respects ADrive acts as a “data controller” of its EU customers’ personal information (e.g., user names, passwords, and other basic personal data necessary to become a user and navigate ADrive’s services). As such, ADrive has implemented appropriate technical and organizational measures, including a robust privacy policy, to ensure and to be able to demonstrate that any processing is performed in accordance with the GDPR at all times. Said measures are reviewed and updated where necessary.

Primarily, however, as an independent cloud-based data storage and hosting service, to the extent ADrive’s services implicate the GDPR, ADrive is a “data processor” with respect to personal information, namely personal information that may from time to time be uploaded by ADrive’s users without ADrive’s specific foreknowledge or control. Where such activities occur, ADrive has committed to the following:   

  * Wherever processing is to be carried out by another party, on behalf of ADrive or any other party, ADrive is committed to implementing appropriate technical and organizational measures in such a manner that processing will meet the requirements of the GDPR and ensure the protection of the rights of all data subjects. 

  * ADrive will not itself, or on behalf of any of its customers or users, engage any other processor to perform processing activities without prior specific or general written authorization of the controller of such information. 

  * With respect to data control and data processing, ADrive has implemented, and will continue to implement, appropriate technical and organizational measures, including security measures, that are designed to implement data-protection principles in an effective manner and to integrate the necessary safeguards into the processing in order to meet the requirements of the GDPR and to protect data subjects. Among other things ADrive utilizes SSL encryption and similar industry standard practices to ensure the ongoing confidentiality, integrity, availability, and resilience of processing systems and services. ADrive also utilizes secure server architecture with multiple layers of protection, designed with redundancies to ensure reliability. ADrive further develops and implements network security and monitoring techniques designed to root out potential threats, as well as incorporates appropriate physical security measures to ensure data protection. 

  * ADrive has the ability to restore the availability and access to personal data in a timely manner in the event of a physical or technical incident, as well as a process for regularly testing, assessing and evaluating the effectiveness or its security measures. 

  * Any natural person acting under the authority of ADrive, who has access to personal data of EU citizens, shall only process it in accordance with strict instructions from the controller, unless he or she is required to do so by intervening legal authorities. 

  * How ADrive users can access personal information:
    1. ADrive users are entitled to ask ADrive for an electronic copy of personal information (i.e., information in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format), to erase it, or to restrict its processing. Users also have rights to object to some processing that is based on ADrive or its users’ legitimate interests, such as profiling, marketing, and related activities. Where ADrive has asked users for consent to processing activities, users retain the right to withdraw their consent – although in certain instances, ADrive may be able to retain some data, even if consent is withdrawn, if ADrive can demonstrate it has a legal requirement to process said information. 

    2. Where ADrive requires You to supply personal information to comply with legal or contractual obligations, then provision of such data is mandatory; if such data is not provided, then we will not be able to manage our contractual relationship with YOU, or to meet ADrive’s obligations placed upon it. In all other cases, provision of the requested information is optional. 

    3. If You have unresolved concerns, You also have the right to complain to data protection authorities. The relevant data protection authority will be the data protection authority of the country: (i) of your habitual residence; (ii) of your place of work; or (iii) in which you consider the alleged infringement has occurred. 

  * If you have any questions about our privacy practices or the way in which ADrive has been managing your personal information, please contact our privacy manager in writing at 1321 67th Street, Emeryville, CA 94608 or [support@ADrive.com](mailto:support@ADrive.com). 

  * The foregoing provisions of this Section “N” shall apply to the processing and control of Personal Data of EU Citizens only and shall be of no force or effect to persons in any jurisdictions outside those explicitly subject to the GDRP. 

### O. Updates to Privacy Policy.

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time, and will post the most current version on our website. If a revision meaningfully reduces Your rights, we will notify You. 

If we are involved in a reorganization, merger, acquisition or sale of our assets, Your information may be transferred as part of that deal. We will notify You (for example, via a message to the email address associated with Your account) of any such deal and outline Your choices in that event.
